# 茯苓糕 心情不好的时候吃点茯苓糕
Fulin Cake When you are in a bad mood, enjoy some Fulin Cake
# 茯苓是养颜美容
Poria helps you stay young
# 大米粉一斤
500 grams of rice flour
# 糯米粉一两
50 grams of glutinous rice flour
# 大米粉就大米磨的粉
Rice flour is milled rice
# 然后糯米粉就是包元宵那个 糯米
Then the glutinous rice flour is the glutinous rice that are used for Yuanxiao
# 茯苓粉 这也是五十克
Poria powder, this is also 50 grams
# 茯苓粉也是一两 两个一两
Poria powder is also 50 grams
# 掺在一起三个粉子
Mix three powders together
# 茯苓粉 糯米粉 大米粉混在一起
Poria flour, glutinous rice flour, rice flour mixed together
# 牛奶 一盒牛奶看看够不够
Milk, see if a carton of milk is enough
# 不够的再接着来
Add more if not enough
# 还有放豆浆也行 正宗的是放豆浆
Soy milk is also OK, the authentic one is soy milk
# 还是牛奶好
Milk is better
# 茯苓糕 这个小吃好
Fulin Cake This snack is good
# 心情不好的时候吃点茯苓糕
Have some poria cakes when you are in a bad mood
# 和成潮乎的那种
Mix the dough to the moisture kind
# 那也差不多
That's almost the same
# 一袋奶不够 又来一袋
One bag of milk is not enough, another bag
# 这茯苓粉还真能吃水
This tuckahoe powder can really absorb water
# 我看这盒有多大 两百五十毫升
I see how big this box is, 250 ml
# 有这种疙瘩 一攥成坨
Mix it till it has this kind of lumps
# 一攥成这样似的
It looks like this
# 这就跟过去蒸什么似的
It's like steaming that in the past
# 蒸干面粉似 一点点搓出来
It’s like steaming dry flour and rubbing it out a little bit
# 把它拌匀了
Mix it well
# 面点小吃 配方特别严谨
Pastry snacks formula is particularly rigorous
# 你看这米粉含水量低
You see the rice noodles have low water content
# 它吃水量就高
It absorbs a lot of water
# 行了这就 好了
That's it
# （牛奶）大约在六两 三百克
(Milk) About six to two to three hundred grams
# 我得把它过一下（箩） 还得过一下
I have to pass it through a sieve
# 不过口感没有那样的不松软
But the taste is not as soft
# 下次老饭骨得买个箩了 面箩
I have to buy a sieve next time. flour sieve
# 买个40目的 买个60目的
Buy one with 40 mesh buy one with 60 mesh
# 再来一个80目的
Another 80 mesh
# 80目用的少 80目一般箩面用的
80 mesh is used not as frequent, 80 mesh is generally used for flour
# 直接弄怎么着啊
What's the matter?
# 直接弄全是疙瘩 必须得要这样式的
Or else it will be full of lumps
# 这样式蒸出来的糕它才松散
This style of steamed cake is loose
# 好 师父这就过完了 特别细啊
OK, Master, this is over
# 过完咱拿湿布盖上它饧一会
After that, let's cover it with a wet cloth for a while
# 饧一会咱炒馅儿
Let's fry stuffing for a while
# 把芝麻炒一下 小火慢炒
Lightly roast the sesame seeds
# 这茯苓糕有100多年历史了
This Fulin cake has a history of more than 100 years
# 行了
okay
# 金黄色
Golden
# 桂花 干桂花 一两
Osmanthus dried osmanthus 50g
# 这芝麻一配干桂花这香味
This sesame is matched with the fragrance of dried osmanthus
# 哗就出来了 激发出来了
Wow came out, emerging out
# 这甜点必须得甜 你不甜就没味道
This dessert must be sweet. If it is not sweet, it has no taste
# 100多年前就做出这么好的东西来
Made such a good thing more than 100 years ago
# 老祖宗留下来的
From the ancestors
# 老祖宗的智慧太深了
The wisdom of the ancestors is too deep
# 为什么要讲传承呢
Why we talk about inheritance?
# 再来点猪油 更润一些
Some more lard to soften it up a little
# 猪油增加香气 又不上色
Lard increases the aroma without coloring
# 桂花芝麻白糖馅
Osmanthus and sesame sugar filling
# 过去做点心基本都是大油
In the past, making dim sum was mostly lard
# 这是传承的 香
This is inherited, incense
# 行了 咱开蒸
OK, let's steam it
# 还带一小屉儿 一个屉一个模子
I also bring a small drawer, a drawer and a mold
# 没有这个放到碗里也行
Put it in a bowl if you don’t have this
# 轻轻的 撒在里面
Sprinkle it gently
# 把它弄匀了
Smooth it out
# 在里蒸个小发糕都行是吧
Steam a small hair cake in it, right?
# 之后来层馅儿
Layer stuffing later
# 可大可小（可多可少）
Can be big or small (more or less)
# 要说你看做点心 也不能小看它
If you think of it as a snack, you can’t underestimate it
# 一个小吃的点心 智慧非常大
A snack of dim sum, very smart
# 做几层都行 咱们就一层
It’s okay to make several layers, we just have one layer
# 想做几层做几层
Want to do a few layers
# 就看这模子的高矮了
It depends on the height of this model
# 再来一层粉子
Another layer of powder
# 好嘞
okay
# 这也不用压 不用压
No need to press, no need to press
# 我们放里边
We put it inside
# 一蒸 蒸多久呢 二十五分钟
How long does it take to steam for 25 minutes
# 好嘞 歇会儿您
Okay, take a break for you
# 好了时间到了
It's time
# 出锅 快看看吧 漂亮
Come out, take a look, pretty
# 实际上这就跟米糕似的
It's actually like rice cakes
# 还真蒸瓷实了
Really steamed stiff
# 你瞧瞧你瞧瞧
You see you see
# 来点桂花上面
Some sweet-scented osmanthus
# 拿小刀轻轻的一压
Take a knife and lightly press
# 它这个最好是晾十分钟（再切）
It’s best to let it dry for ten minutes (cut it again)
# 锯切 不能直切
Don’t cut it straight
# 它凉了它就挺住了
When it gets cold, it holds up
# 它一凉就挺住了
It holds up when it cools
# 家里在碗里蒸就行
Just steam it in a bowl at home
# 咱大晚上不能吃那么多甜的
We can't eat so much sweets at night
# 好吃
Delicious!
# 这块儿也太大 太多了
This piece is too big, too much
# 但是它不噎人
But it doesn't choke
# 有传承 有技艺 还有创新
There is inheritance, skills and innovation
# 米香 桂花香 茯苓的香 还有芝麻香
Rice fragrance, osmanthus fragrance, Poria fragrance and sesame fragrance
# 四香合为一体
Four incense into one
# 经典小吃 赞
Classic snacks
# 雨夜重生问
A friend asks
# 请问秋葵怎么处理才能不黏
How to handle okra so that it is not sticky
# 每次烫完都觉得很黏
I feel very sticky every time I blench it
# 秋葵本身就带黏液
Okra itself has mucus
# 对人体是非常有益的
Is very beneficial to our body
# 但是有的人吃起来
But some people eat
# 觉得它糊嘴
Feel like too sticky
# 口感不好
Bad taste
# 其实我们在烫完之后
In fact, after we finish blenching
# 然后我们先拿凉水
Then we first take cold water
# 给它冲凉
Rinse it cold
# 冲凉以后可以少搁一点盐
You can put a little less salt after cooled
# 搁点儿醋拌一拌
Put a little vinegar and mix it
# 然后再拿水冲
Then rinse with water
# 冲完以后冰水再镇一下
After rinsing is finished
# 你切丝切条
You can shred or slice
# 然后再进行腌制
Then marinate
# 吃辣味的还是吃香油味的
Spicy or sesame oil
# 还是吃三合油的
Or eat mixed oils
# 还是吃芝麻酱的还是吃怪味的
Still eat the sesame sauce or the Guaiwei
# 调味的方式
Way of seasoning
# 你再另外去选择
You choose another
# 那黏液就会下来
The slime will come down
# 因为它有醋
Because it has vinegar
# 醋你看洗鱼 猪肚
Vinegar, you can also use in washing fish and pork stomach
# 鳗鱼鳝鱼
Eel or unagi
# 凡是有黏液比较重的
Anything with heavier mucus
# 用醋来拿它就能撤掉一部分
Take it with vinegar to remove part of it
# 切完了以后它肯定是黏的
It must be sticky after cutting
# 搁那水里边搁点醋搁点盐 你搓搓它
Put some vinegar in the water and some salt, you rub it
# 洗肥肠一样
Just like washing intestines
# 洗洗它搓一搓 然后最后一焯水
Wash it, rub it, and blanch it at the end
# 搁在冰水里边一镇
Put a town in ice water
# 再漂漂它
Let it sit for a while
# 这个就利索了 分你怎么吃
This is neat, depends on how do you eat
# 你要分白灼 灼完了之后
If you need to blench
# 它就没有黏液带着这汁儿
It wont have as much mucus with this juice
# 热吃冷吃都可以
Have it hot or cold
# 好的谢谢
Okay thank you
# 不可以
You cant
# 不刷锅
Leave the wok unwashed
# 你炒下一个菜
To continue the next dish
# 一会是会使下一个菜
Will make the next dish
# 菜不干净
Dishes are not clean
# 里边会有一些黑渣子
There will be some black scum inside
# 另外不刷锅
Also don't wash the wok
# 可能要炒一些肉菜
Maybe some meat dishes
# 它会粘锅
It will stick
# 炒肉菜也不好吃
meat dishes are not delicious with it
# 比如红烧肉
Such as braised pork
# 我们要放盐
If we put salt in
# 那肉 肉质就比较紧巴了
The meat is tighter
# 比如我们后放 做一些汤
For example, after we put it in to make some soup
# 也需要后边
Also need back
# 调这个味道
Adjust this taste
# 根据不同的菜品来定
According to different dishes
# 冒烟不是说
Smoking doesn't mean
# 油锅冒烟有多好
How good is the oil pan smoking
# 有些爆炒的菜
Some stir-fried dishes
# 但也不是油锅冒烟才炒的
But don’t wait till the frying pan smokes.
# 油温达到一个7成8成
The oil temperature reaches 210-240C
# 这基本油就要冒烟了
This oil is about to smoke
# 像什么爆羊肉
Like fried lamb
# 就可以用这种
You can use this
# 急火旺炒 急火旺炒
Stir-fry
# 是盐搁的少淀粉不够
The salt is too little as well as starch
# 我们现在改良的干炸丸子
Our improved ganzha meat balls
# 你要不搁冰箱里镇它一宿
If you dont put it in the refrigerator overnight
# 炸丸子还真炸不出来
The meat ball can't be fried with it’s shape
# 现在很多餐厅
Many restaurants now
# 为了节省成本
In order to save costs
# 高汤都用添加剂代替
The broth is full of additives
# 想请问一下
Would like to ask
# 就关于这个问题您怎么看
What do you think about this issue
# 有一些餐厅为了节约成本
There are some restaurants in order to save costs
# 用添加剂代替
Replace with additives
# 常说的一句话
A word often said
# 做要想做好菜
To cook a good dish
# 必须要一个好汤
Must have a good soup
# 用添加剂是取代不了的
Additives can’t replace good soup
# 请问一下二伯
I would like to ask Erbai
# 对于上浆的手法
The technique of coating starch
# 有专业的要求吗
Are there any professional requirements?
# 对于上浆的时候
For coating starch
# 这些调料的顺序都是什么样的
What is the order of these seasonings
# 它是根据我们原材料
It is based on our ingredients
# 根据烹饪的需求
According to cooking needs
# 大概的顺序
Approximate order
# 比如说葱姜水蛋清的顺序
For example, the order of spring onion and ginger egg white
# 根据原材料的不同性质
According to the different nature of ingredients
# 一般的情况下
Under normal circumstances
# 都是先打葱姜水
Always make scallion ginger water first
# 逐步下分层次的下然后呢
Step by step
# 把这水全吃进去
Absorb all this water
# 比如肉变的非常润了
For example, the meat becomes very moist
# 再调味
Then season it
# 再把这东西
Put this thing
# 再打进去
In again
# 这样才封的住```
This way you can seal it up